# Jake Williams

# Runner

+44 (0) 7505 555 717 <u>jake@jpwfilm.co.uk</u> jpwfilm.co.uk

#### **SKILLS**

I have experience and training on a wide range of cameras, lighting and grip equipment, additionally I'm familiar with **Adobe Creative Suite** including, but not limited to, **Premiere Pro**, **Photoshop**, and **Audition**. I'm a hard worker with a wide range of experience in many different areas, which helped me develop my **leadership**, **problem solving**, **team working**, and **time management** skills.

### **INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE**

#### Freelance /

## Corporate & Event Filming

SEPTEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

I ensure the clients' brief is met with a creative and professional piece of work. In the past I've worked with theatre companies, corporations, and universities. I adapted my working style for each client to be as efficient as possible while maintaining quality.

## **Event Manager; Filmmaker Liaison /**

# Winchester Film Festival

2018 & 2019, WINCHESTER

During my time volunteering for the festival, I successfully organised an awards ceremony and a filmmaker's social, along with nightly film screenings. Under time pressures, I had to manage myself in order to deliver my assistance to the founder, oversee student teams, and complete my own tasks.

# NON-INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

# Nanny

APRIL 2018 - MAY 2020

## Senior Travel Trainer /

Norfolk County Council

2017 - 2019

### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

**Helper** | Hampshire Pride (2019) **Scout Troop Assistant** (2013-2020)

## 1st AD and more /

#### Student Films

SEPTEMBER 2017 - MAY 2020, WINCHESTER

I've performed rudimentary roles on student film sets and I'm ready to take them to the next level. These include: 1st AD, Script Supervisor, Producer, Writer, and Runner. In each case I had to learn on the job and worked tirelessly to deliver in the role.

### **Production Coordinator /**

## 'Downtime'

2018, WINCHESTER

A co-creation project between students and lectures, I oversaw the communication between the departments, attended location recces to assist department heads, and worked on set as a **3rd AD** and **Runner**.

# **EDUCATION**

## BA (Hons) Film Production /

University of Winchester

2017 - 2020

Recent graduate with a predicted result of 2:1.

### **PAST EMPLOYERS**

University of Winchester Winchester Poetry Festival Winchester Theatre Royal